イカサマ シゴロ賽を
見破ったカイジ
Kaiji, seeing through the loaded dice, catches Foreman Ohtsuki out!
ついに班長 大槻を追い詰める
Applause, And...
No way! You've got to be kidding!
じょ… 冗談じゃない
そんなこと！
いや 筋は通っている
No, that makes sense.
積み重ねてきたロジック
Kaiji's logic makes sense to me.
理はワシが見る限り
カイジ君にある
だ… 誰だ あんたは！
一体なんの権利があって…
Who the hell are you!?
Where do you get off—
こら！口を慎め 大槻！
Shut up, Ohtsuki!
このお方は帝愛グループ
最高幹部の一人
This man is on Teiai Group's board! Second only to our great leader President Hyodo!
偉大なる総帥
兵藤会長の次に位置する
この王国のナンバー２
This kingdom's number two! You're talking to Yoshihiro Kurosaki!
黒崎義裕様であられるぞ
ええっ！
控えろ！控えろ 控えろ
Back off! Now!
消し飛ぶぞ！
お前のようなゴミクズ！
Get out of here, you scum!
This man can send you to far deeper, crueler pits than this one just by pointing a finger!
この方の指先ひとつで
この地下よりも
さらに過酷な地下の地下まで！
控えろ！
So back off!
も… 申し訳ございません！
I'm terribly sorry! Please forgive me!
お許しを！
いいかな？その賽
Can I see those dice?
Hmm.
どれ？
うん　何かの骨だな これは
These are made out of bone, aren't they?
それは奴が
これ見よがしに食っていた
Bones from the T-bone steaks he ate in front of us.
Ｔボーンステーキの骨
そいつをトイレで少しずつ削って
サイコロの形にし
We shaved them down using the toilets into the shape of dice.
ピンの赤は俺の血をすり込んだ
The red dots are our blood.
フフッ なるほど
I see, I see.
なるほど フフッ
I see.
大槻とやら　仕方ないな これは
Ohtsuki didn't leave you any other choice, did he?
お前は絡め取られたんだ
You've been caught.
お前が今まで
ここの連中にしてきたように
Netted by a thorough plan just like the one you've been springing on the inmates here.
綿密に用意 計画され
絡め取られた
So you can dish it out but you can't take it, I see?
他人にはするが
自分がされた時は ご免こうむる
通らないだろ
いくらなんでも それは
That's just no good at all.
You only use the loaded dice on a dealer's second turn.
この親２回に限っては
特殊賽を仲間内で回して使う
ということで
勝負を続行するしかない
That way people can't avoid them.
黒崎様　勘弁してください！
Please, Mr. Kurosaki!
この金は 私がコツコツ
営々 蓄えてきた汗の結晶でして
I've poured blood, sweat, and tears into saving up this money!
それをこんな こんな必ず負けると
知っているギャンブルで…
I can't lose it all on a bet I'm guaranteed not to win!
いやいや そうとは限らんぞ
Now that's not true.
確かにこの勝負
シゴロ賽を使えば負けは必至
If you use the 4-5-6 dice you're sure to lose.
100パーセント負ける勝負だが
普通の賽を使えば
引き分けの目は出てくる
But if you use normal dice, you can draw.
216分の１ほどの確率で
You've got 1-in-216 odds.
く… 黒崎様
Mr. Kurosaki!
ここは潔く
それに懸けるしかあるまい
Man up and roll the dice.
黒崎様　それはあまりに…
Mr. Kurosaki! That's too—
こら！往生際が悪いぞ
Don't you know when to give up!?
そうだそうだ！
やれ 大槻！
Yeah!
Roll 'em, Ohtsuki!
さっさとやれよ！
どうした どうした！
Go ahead and roll!
What's wrong?
言ってたじゃねえか お前
念じる力で目が出るんだろ？
It was your own idea!
You can make the dice come up how you want just by thinking about it, right!?
そうだそうだ！
やってみろ　やれ！
Yeah!
So go ahead and do it!
石和…
Isawa...
沼川…
Numakawa...
この夜のチンチロ勝負
大槻 対 カイジ
The late-night chinchiro duel between Ohtsuki and Kaiji approaches its end!
ついに決着の時を迎える
Even Ohtsuki cannot resist Kurosaki's judgment.
黒崎の審判とあっては
大槻もあらがえず
仕方なく普通の賽を取る
With no choice, he takes up normal dice!
His prayer, snake eyes and a miraculous draw!
願いは引き分けとなる
奇跡のピンゾロ
But he is not so fortunate! His roll is a 3!
しかし そんな調子のよいことは
そうそう起こるはずもなく
出目は３
当然 負ける
He loses, of course.
He loses.
負ける　負ける
He loses!
負ける！負け続ける！
He loses!!!
He keeps losing!
And he coughs up the dirty money he'd squirreled away!
そして吐き出す！ここまで
蓄えてきた汚れた金ほとんどを
All that remains in his safe is 1,800 perica!
結局 金庫に残ったのは
たった1800ペリカ
Ohtsuki is crushed! The biggest defeat in underground chinchiro history!
大槻 大敗！
地下チンチロ史上最大 歴史的大敗
一方 カイジらは
目のくらむような大勝！
Kaiji, on the other hand, has scored a dazzling victory!
合計 1825万2000ペリカ
A total of 18,252,000 perica!
一人頭 およそ304万ペリカ
Around 3,040,000 perica each!
Impossible... Impossible!
バカな… バカな
Why?
なんで こんな
夢みたいなことが 現実に
This is like a dream! It can't be real!
Why? Why!?
なぜ… どうして
えっ 均等に山分け？
So we split it evenly?
Yeah.
そうだ　この金は
４５組の６人で均等に分けるんだ
All six of us 45s split it even.
でもカイジさんが
一番 頑張ったんだから
You did most of the work, Kaiji. No one's going to mind if you—
少しくらい多く取っても
誰も文句は…
なーに言ってんだよ
What are you talking about?
この金は みんなで何ヵ月も
頑張って手にした給料が元手
We all killed ourselves for months earning the money we started with
そんな金に差別も区別もあるかよ
みんな平等だ
I can't give myself extra out of that money. We're all even.
ほんとに いいんですか？
You sure!?
当たり前だ
カ… カイジさんは
Of course!
Kaiji, you're...
なんて… なんていい人なんだ！
You're such a great guy!
おいおい 逆だって
いい人は お前らのほうだって
No, no! It's all you guys!
みんな何も言わずに
黙って ついてきてくれた
You kept quiet and went along with my plan.
今回の勝ちのネタを
一切 聞こうとせず
You didn't need to hear anything about how I was going to win, you just believed in me.
俺を信じて ついてきてくれた
That's not an easy thing to do.
なかなか
できることじゃねえよ それ
普通は聞き出そうとするって
Most people would ask. It was a lot of money, after all.
大金が懸かってるんだから
けど お前らはそれをしなかった
But you didn't. I couldn't believe it.
あり得ないんだよ そんなこと
だからこそ
それが決定的勝因になった
And really, that's why we won.
勝因？
そうさ
Why we won?
Yeah. That's what really tripped the Foreman up.
あの班長が今回
一番 見誤ったのは
まさにその点なんだ
人は人を手放しに
信じたりしないってのが
A guy like him just can't understand people believing in each other like that.
奴の考えの根幹 常識
It's obvious.
So I knew he'd be wrong about why you didn't react when he didn't use the 4-5-6 dice.
だからこそ 第１投で
シゴロ賽を使わないことへの
みんなの無反応を
奴は100パーセント誤解した
シゴロ賽は気づかれていないと
誤解した
That he'd assume we didn't know his trick.
そのミスジャッジがなけりゃ
今回のこの大勝ちはない
Without that misjudgment, we wouldn't have won like this.
みんなの俺への信頼が
勝ちを引き寄せた
Your trust in me was what let us win!
Really, guys. Thanks.
だから みんなには
ほんとに感謝してるんだ
Kaiji...
カイジさん
あっ ちょ… ちょっと大将
ん？
Wait, boss!
大将
ワシのことか？
Boss!
You mean me?
帰っちまう前に約束してくれ
そこの外出券の項目には
Promise me before you leave!
Do something about that one condition on the furlough!
気持ち悪い１文が
くっついてるじゃねえか
１日50万ペリカで出すかどうかは
The 500,000 perica part is fine, but the "judgment of Teiai" thing...
帝愛が適正と判断した場合に
限るとかなんとか
んん… そういうことになるな
それが？
Oh, that? Well...
せっかく ここまで
もってきたんだ
Look at how far we've come!
変な難癖つけずに
すんなり出してくれんだろうな
You can't keep us in here on some weird technicality!
カイジ君
これは難癖とかではなくて
Kaiji, this isn't just a technicality.
ここでの しきたりとして
落ちて１年未満の者は
No one leaves this pit during their first year.
出したりしないんだ
時期尚早ということでな
It's simply not time yet.
が まあしかし ここまで
大ごとになったら そうもいくまい
But I suppose we have to do something.
今ここで 君らのその願いを
無下に突っぱねると
If we grant that wish of yours right here, right now, it wouldn't be fair to the others.
他の者の手前 よろしくない
全体の労働意欲に影響する
We can't have it reducing their will to work.
じゃあ…
認めよう
Then...
Very well. Do as you wish.
好きにするがいい
All right!
やった！
カイジさん！
Kaiji!
しかし出てどうするつもりだ？
But what do you plan on doing on the outside?
Fifteen million perica. Three million each.
約1800万
一人ずつ割れば300万ペリカ
That's 300,000 yen.
日本円に直せば30万だ
そこから１日出るなら５万
50,000 of that goes to the furlough.
２日なら10万引かれ
手にする金は20万か25万
100,000 if you stay out for two days. You'll only have 200,000 or 250,000 yen.
それっぽっちの金で
１日２日 外に行き
What can you do in a day or two with that little money?
どうしようというのだ？
あるのか？1000万近い借金を
返済する当てでも
Can you really repay almost ten million with that?
あるさ！ある
Of course I can! Yeah!
というと？
ギャンブルだ
And how?
I'll gamble! If I can win fifty times that 200,000 in two days, there's my ten million!
２日出て20万
その金を50倍にすれば1000万
それができなかったから お前らは
今ここにいるんじゃないのか？
Remember, you're here because you couldn't do that.
フッ 分からん男だな カイジ君
I don't understand you, Kaiji.
君はバカか利口か分からん男
I can't tell if you're a fool or a genius.
しかし まあいい
好きにしたまえ
Very well. Do as you will. We'll meet again in a few days.
また会おうじゃないか 数日後
恐らくは またここで フフフッ
Here again, if I'm correct.
クッ ふざけるな
No fucking way!
一度出たら
誰が戻るかよ こんなとこ！
Who the hell would come back here once they get out!?
I'll win... I'll win because I have to...
勝ってやる
死にものぐるいで勝って
勝って勝って 勝って獲得する
I'll win! I'll win!
I'll win back my freedom!
必ず自由を！
Light! Sunlight!
日だ　日の光だ
Kaiji is reborn! Freed!
カイジ 生還！解放される
過酷な地下暮らしの収容所から
一時的に
Freed, for a moment, from his cruel torment beneath the earth!
きれいな水
Clean water...
Fresh air...
新鮮な空気
And...
それに…
There it is! My money!
ある！金
Real money! Yen!
本物の金　日本円
All right!
やった！帰ってきた この世界に
I'm back! Back in the real world!
Kaiji feels bliss!
カイジ 至福の時
だが しかし！
But! But!!!
At that moment, the countdown begins!
この瞬間から
カウントダウンが始まる！
動き出す　カイジのシャバでの
残り時間を示す
The watch counting down Kaiji's time out the outside begins to tick!
時計が！
10 11 12 13 14 15 16
Hundred, 110, 120, 130, 140, 150, 160...
17 18 19 20
170, 180, 190, two hundred, 210, 220, 230...
21 22 23…
託す？
はい
Wait, extra?
Yes. We all talked it over.
実は みんなで
話し合っていたんです
We thought you might win big, so we all chipped in a bit more for you to bet!
もし今回の博打が
思いもかけない大勝ちになったら
その金をカイジさんに託して
勝負してもらおうって
What!?
ああ？
別行動で20万を1000万にするより
We're more likely to win having you bet than each trying to turn 200 thou into ten million!
カイジさんに預けて
勝負してもらうのが
一番 確率が高いんです
バカ言うな！
1000万あれば自由になれるのに
Dumbass! Who the hell do you think's gonna risk it after they've got their 10 mil?
誰が危険を冒して
お前らの分まで勝とうとするかよ
You guys are really easy marks.
お人よしも いい加減にしろ
お言葉ですが カイジさんだって
Wait, didn't you say before we should split it all evenly?
もっと分け前もらっていいのに
均等なんて
俺たち同様 お人よしっていうか
ちょっと抜けてるっていうか…
You're just as bad as us.
ああ いや！
単なるお人よしだったら
Well, if that's all you were, we wouldn't have given you our money.
俺たちの大事な金
託したりしませんよ
カイジさん
人がいいだけじゃなくて
You may be a nice guy, but you're... I dunno. Clever, or sharp, or something!
したたかっていうか
切れるんです
間違いなく この中で
一番勝つ確率の高い人
You're the one of us most likely to win!
なーに言ってんだよ！
分かるか そんなこと
Seriously? What the hell are you talking about!?
じゃ あのネタ教えてくださいよ
Then tell us how you did it!
ほら ３ヵ月前
みんなで決起した夜に
Three months ago, when we all got together! You guessed it!
カイジさんは
言い当てたじゃないですか
Guessed that the Foreman would roll a 4-5-6!
班長の出目をシゴロだって
Now that I think about it, it wasn't a sure thing.
あれって今考えたら
絶対シゴロってわけないですよね
シゴロ賽でシゴロが出る確率は
２割くらい
Even with the 4-5-6 dice, the odds of an actual 4-5-6 are only about one in five.
外れる可能性のほうが高かった
You were more likely to be wrong than right.
外したら どうするつもりでした？
What would you have done if you were wrong?
The same thing.
同じだ
同じ？
The same thing?
仮にシゴロでなくても
その目は４４５とか５５６とか
Even if he didn't roll a 4-5-6, it would've been something close like a 4-4-5 or 5-5-6.
かなりシゴロに近い目に
なっている
そういう外し方は
それはそれで信用を勝ち取れる
That near of a miss would have been enough to make you believe me.
そこ！
え？
That's it!
そういうところ！
お人よしプラスその抜け目なさ
That's what it is! You're a nice guy, but then you've got that sharp edge!
乗らせてください その博才に！
お願いします！
Teach us how to gamble like that!
Please!
780. 790. Eight hundred.
78 79 80
そして1800万ペリカ
日本円にして180万を
And thus 18,000,000 perica—1,800,000 yen—
20日外出する権利と
80万の現金に振り分けたのだ！
were split into twenty days of furlough and 800,000 yen!
あいつらときたら お人よし
バカどもだ
Those idiots really think I'm a nice guy.
Dammit!
クソッ おかげで ますます
負けられなくなったじゃねえか！
Now I really can't lose!
He is tasked with a miracle!
課せられたのは奇跡
A miracle beyond his victory in underground chinchiro!
あの地下チンチロ以上の大勝
そんなミラクル
カイジは その元金80万を
Kaiji has 20 days to turn 800,000 yen into over 60 million, enough to buy freedom for all!
20日間で６人分の借金に当たる
6000万強にしなければならない
正確には6075万
The total, 60,750,000!
It's pointless playing around in a place like this.
こんな お遊びカジノじゃ
話になんねえ
あっ…
気をつけろ！
Jeez, watch it!
Oh, sorry.
ああ　悪い
Legal gambling isn't gonna get me there. I've gotta go to the underworld.
表はダメだ　裏だ
Somewhere where I can figure out their game.
勝つ仕組みを築いている所
つまりイカサマを
仕組んでいるような所
That is, somewhere that's cheating.
そんな仕組みがあるってことは
In a shady place like that, I know I can win.
逆にその裏さえ突けば 必ず勝てる
Hey there.
兄さん
あ？
Yeah?
You look pretty loaded. How's 'bout sharin' the wealth?
ずいぶん持ってるじゃないの
少し回してよ
おとなしく渡せば
刺したりなんかしねえよ
Cough up and I ain't gonna hafta cut ya.
大ごとだぞ　刺したら
You sure you want to do that?
あ？
お前らの顔 覚えたからな
I've seen your faces.
多勢に無勢　ここでやられても
You may have me outnumbered here, but we'll find you, tie you up...
あとで捜し出して
全員 事務所に監禁し
死ぬほど後悔させてやる
And give you something worse than death.
We'll lop 'em off one by one. Like this.
１本１本 落としてやろうか？
こんなふうに
Holy shit!
ヤ… ヤバいよ
す… すみませんでした！
We're sorry!
ヘヘヘッ
うまくしのいだな 兄さん
Good job weaseling out of that one.
But the real thing doesn't stick their fingers back on.
そんなふうに
指を取ったり くっつけたり
ほんまモンが やることやない
今のはハッタリ
あんた 偽モンだ
That was a bluff. You're a fake.
誰だ お前
Who the hell are you!?
安心せえ　ワシはなんもせんて
Don't worry. I'm not gonna do anything to you.
いや むしろ逆
Actually...
いいしのぎ方だったと
感心しとるんだ
That trick of yours was pretty impressive.
You may be a good pick.
あんたなら頼めるかもしれんな
How about it? Wanna go in with me on something?
どうよ　組まんか ワシと？
There's this interesting casino I know.
面白いカジノへ連れていってやる
Why don't we go there?
ついといで　よかったら
I've been looking for the right young guy in these casinos for the past three days.
探しとったがよ　３日ほど
いろんなカジノを回って
使えそうな若モンを
これが なかなかいなくてな
The right type is hard to find.
But I can tell you're it.
だが あんたからは感じたんよ
何がなんでも勝とうってオーラ
That aura of wanting to win at anything, whether it's legal or not.
そのためだったら 犯罪だって
いとわないって気配 面構え
That expression on your face. I like it.
気に入ったよ フッ
Here we are.
ここだ
え？
An ordinary, unassuming building!
そこは なんの変哲もない
普通のビル
It's Sakazaki.
坂崎です
Go ahead.
どうぞ
ほんとにカジノだ！
It really is a casino!
確かにカジノ！
A casino, indeed! A high-stakes illegal casino!
しかも とんでもない高額が
乱れ飛ぶ 裏カジノ！
And there's more!
そして さらに！
What!?
な… なんだ？
These are... Pachinko machines!?
これは… パチンコ
カジノでパチンコ？
Pachinko machines in a casino!?
面白かろう？これが
このカジノの売りだ
Interesting, huh? This is this casino's draw.
24時間営業の高レートパチンコ
24-hour, high-rate pachinko.
通常のパチンコは１玉４円
Normal pachinko is 4 yen a ball.
ここはそれの10倍の40円
Over here, it's ten times that, 40 yen.
あるいは100倍の
400円の台まである
And here, it's 400 yen, 100 times normal.
100倍？
100 times!?
うおっ！
来た？来たー！
There it is!
There it is!!!
なんだ あれは？
What's that!?
That's the real draw. The king of all pachinko machines
ここの目玉のパチンコ台
裏パチすべての王 頂点
It's 1000 times the normal bet. Each ball is 4,000 yen.
1000倍台　１玉4000円のパチンコ
Each ball is 4,000 yen!?
１玉4000円？
Come on!
来て！来てくれ　頼む！頼む！
Please! Please!
ヘヘヘヘッ
あの台に限り デジパチではなく
And that's not a computerized machine. It's an old-style jackpot.
昔ながらの一発台でな
ほれ あの台の最後の難関
３連クルーンをかいくぐって
If you drop a ball through the three trays at the end...
一番下の奥にある 当たりに入れば
You win all the balls previous losers have dumped in.
今まで積み上げてきた敗者の玉を
一気に獲得できる
つまり奴が座っている
あの足元の玉すべてを
All the balls he's sitting on right now.
すべてって！あの玉の１つ１つが
4000円なんだろ？一体いくらに…
All of them!?
Each ball is 4,000 yen, right!?
How many are there!?
Each of those trays holds about a hundred million's worth.
あの横線の１本ごとに約１億だ
つまり今 出たら約５億5000万か
So the jackpot right now is about 550 million.
500 million!?
５億！
He made it to the second tray!
やった！２段目にも入った！
５億！５億だ 来い！
500 million!
300万のカードを もう５枚
1500万もつぎ込んでる
I've put five three-million cards in! That's 15 million!
もう限界！
I'm almost bust!
おおっ ３段目だ！
The third!
これが最後！最後だ
This is it! This is it!
来てくれー！
Come on!
来るんだー！
Go in!
Sir. You're out of balls.
お客様　玉切れですが
Aww, he almost had it.
惜しかったのになあ
どうかお引き取り願います
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
お客様　お引き取りを
Sir. You need to leave.
出ない 出ない　そう簡単には
You can't hit the jackpot that easily.
確かに あと一歩
あともう一歩で出そう！
But one or two more balls and he may have had it!
ってとこまでは いくがな
Maybe, just maybe!
とんでもない　性悪さ
What terrible luck.
This machine loves to taker you right up to the edge without paying out.
出そうだが決して出ないのが
こいつの特徴
沼　人食い沼だよ こいつは
The bog... This is the man-eating bog!
The jackpot is 500 or 600 million!
出れば５億６億
ついにベールを脱いだ
究極のモンスターマシン
The veil of the ultimate monster machine is lifted!
沼！人食い沼！
The bog! The man-eating bog!
Most people would ask. It was a lot of money, after all.
But you didn't. I couldn't believe it. And really, that's why we won.
＜改ざんＢ－ＣＡＳカードによる
不正視聴は➡
刑法により禁じられた犯罪行為＞
＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?